BABUBHAI S. PATEL

501, Ami Mangal – II, Near AMC Office, Judges Bungalows Road, Bodakdev, Ahmedabad – 380054.

Mobile: +91 9727792807, Phone (Res): +91 79 26855091 Email: bspatel54@gmail.com

(DOB: 1st March 1954)

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

39 years of extensive experience in implementation and management of plant machineries, high-end earthmoving equipments, specialized mining equipments, auxiliary & transport equipments. Focussed towards to Improvement of productivity, achievement of targeted production with cost effectiveness and turning projects as a profit centre. Work Record of improving efficiency, productivity and profitability through process improvement and better maintenance practice.

CORE COMPETENCIES

Strategic Planning	Process Improvement	Project leadership
ERP Implementation	Budget Planning & Cost Control	Parts Procurement & Inventory
Maintenance Scheduling	Proposal Development	Utilisation of Resources

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

GMDC Limited – Head Office, Ahmedabad, Gujarat General Manager (Machinery & Maintenance)

March 2013 - March 2014

Worked as a General Manager (M&M) at Gujarat Mineral Development Corporation Limited (GMDC) - Corporate Head Office, Ahmedabad, Gujarat.

Core job functions include strategic planning of heavy earthmoving machinery, budget planning/cost control, plants maintenance/repairs, proposal development/utilization of resources, maintenance & repairing of mining machinery and transport vehicles.

GMDC Limited - Fluorspar Project, Kadipani, Gujarat Deputy General Manager (Maintenance)

May 2007 - March 2013

Worked as Dy General Manager (Maintenance) at Fluorspar Project, Kadipani, Gujarat (Ore Beneficiation plant & Ambadungar mines). Core Job functions include management, maintenance, planning, repair and overhauling of various plant & mining machineries. Also working as a core committee head on ERP implementation with Capgemini.

<u>Plant Machineries (Benefaction Plant):</u> Jaw crusher, Gyratory crusher, Belt conveyor, Ball Mill, Different type of flotation cells, Dryer, Burner, Bag closing and Bag stitching machine and Various type of process and slurry pumps.

<u>Mining Machineries:</u> Hydraulic excavator, Dumpers, Air compressor and Drilling rings, Pay loaders, Crane, Transport vehicles and other associated mining machineries.

GMDC Limited - Lignite Project, Panandhro, Gujarat Senior Manager (Maint.) & Head of the department Asst. Manager (Maint.)

March 1994 – May 2007 May 1986 – Feb 1992

Worked as Maintenance Head of CME, SME division for 19 years at lignite project Panandhro, one of the

biggest project of GMDC, having an annual production of 80 lacs ton and removal of over burden of 200 lacs Cu.M.

At Panandhro, SME (Specialized Mining Equipment) division & CME (Conventional Mining Equipment) division are comprises of three major workshops and with 18 different sections.

Specialized Mining Equipment (SME) at Panandhro Project:

Bucket Wheel Excavators - 3 Nos.

Mobile Transfer Conveyors – 3 Nos.

Spreader – 1 No.

Stacker - 1 No.

Reclaimer - 1 No.

Tripper Car – 1 No.

Belt Conveyors - 10 Nos. (10 kms in length)

All such equipment of Man-Takraf and Elecon make.

In India after NLC only Lignite Project, Panandhro has such type of giant machineries for excavation of open cast mining activity. These machineries are being used for over burden removal and lignite excavation.

- Managed the machineries from fabrication, erection, commissioning, testing, operation, maintenance, repair of these machineries for 19 years.
- Directly supervised major overhaul and rejuvenation of these machineries.
- Trained at Germany for the erection, maintenance for three months and two months at NLC (Neyveli Lignite Corporation) Neyveli, Tamil Nadu for successful implementation of SME system of Operation & Maintenance.
- Headed the Maintenance and specialized mining equipment with spare part planning, preventive maintenance, conveyor shifting and re-arrangements of conveyors.

Managed a work force of about 250 maintenance personnel including 35 Nos. of Asst. Engineers and 6 Asst. Managers.

Received appreciation from Man Takraf, Germany and GMDC time to time for achieving targets.

Conventional Mining Equipment (CME) at Panandhro Project:

Hydraulic excavators from 0.5 cubic meter to 6 cubic meter capacity. 30 nos.

Dozer D-80 & D-155 A-1, Pipe layer - 14 nos.

Dumper (8 T to 50 Tons) - 50 nos.

Motor Graders - 03.

DG Set from 10KVA to 15000 KVA - 06 nos.

Drill m/c, Jeeps, Tractors, TATA 407 tempo - 35 nos.

Buses, Maintenance van, Diesel Bouser, water tankers - 30 nos.

Portable welding set - 03 nos.

Air Compressors – 04 Nos.

Tyre and crawler mounted cranes (10 M.T to 100 tons capacity) - 04 nos

Dewatering pumps - 15 Nos.

Reverse Osmosis Plant 240kl per day capacity - 1 unit

Other associated workshop machineries

GMDC Limited – Calcined Bauxite Project, Gadhsisa, Gujarat Assistant Manager (Maint.) and Head of Department

Out of 21 years served in Kutch region - GMDC, for 2 years I had been posted for this new project of fabrication, erection, testing & commissioning of Bauxite calcinations plant (150 tons per day) Gadhsisa, Mandvi, Kutch. & the plant was successfully commissioned within delivery schedule.

<u>Machineries:</u> Jaw crusher, Elevators, Cyclones, Vibrating screen, Kiln, Cooler, Oil firing system, Belt conveyors, Transport and Mining machineries

Hindustan Copper Limited - Khetri Copper Complex, Khetrinagar, Rajasthan July 1977 - April 1986 Worked at Hindustan Copper Ltd (Khetri Copper Complex) at khetrinagar (Rajasthan) for 9 years at mining workshop and underground mining machinery division for repair of maintenance.

<u>Machineries:</u> Frontend loader(LHD), Low profile dumpers, Drill machines, Raise climbers, Pneumatic loader, Diesel locomotive, Electric locomotive, Teledyne rock breaker, Dewatering pumps, Transport vehicles and other associated mining machineries.

IFFCO - Indian Farmers Fertiliser Cooperative Limited, Kandla, Kutch, Gujarat Sept. 1976 - July 1977 Worked as a Trainee at IFFCO (Kandla Unit). Worked on Machine shop, Auto Garage, NPK plant, material handling section, bagging section.

CERTIFICATIONS

- A Specialized Mining Equipment Training Program of MAN-TAKRAF at BKK Institute, GERMANY for three months.
- Import Substitution and Indigenous Parts Development and Maintenance Practices at NLC Neyveli.
- Maintenance Management Program at ISM Dhanbad.
- Maintenance Management program at staff engineering college at Hyderabad.
- Engine Maintenance Management at Hindustan Power Ltd (Hosur, Tamil Nadu)
- Sr. Technical Executive Training Program for heavy vehicles at TELCO Pune.
- Preventive Maintenance Program at IIPM Kanshbhal, Orrisa.
- Various OEM training program at vocational centre at GMDC Panandhro, Gujarat.
- 2 years EME NCC training.
- Supply Chain Management training at Nirma University, Ahmedabad.
- Team Effectiveness and Leadership training at Nirma University, Ahmedabad.

EDUCATION

- First class first rank in Diploma Automobile Engineering from Gujarat Technical Education Board GTEB (3.1/2 years)
- Awarded silver jubilee memorial trust prize in 1975 at SBPT Institute Bhavanagar, Gujarat.
- Pre university science at M.G. Science College Ahmedabad, Gujarat 1971.